Call for Abstracts 

The 3rd International Workshop on Bio-Design Automation
June 6 - 7, 2011
Part of the Design Automation ConferenceSan Diego Convention Center
San Diego, California

Workshop Website:
http://www.biodesignautomation.org 
The International Workshop on Bio-Design Automation (IWBDA) brings together researchers from the synthetic biology, systems biology, and design automation communities. The focus is on concepts, methodologies, and software tools to enable the computational analysis of biological systems and the synthesis of biological functions. Still in its early stages, the field of synthetic biology has been driven by experimental expertise; much of its success can be attributed to the skill of the researchers in specific domains of biology. There has been a concerted effort to assemble repositories of standardized components. However, creating and integrating synthetic components remains an ad hoc process. The field has now reached a stage where it calls for computer-aided design tools. The electronic design automation (EDA) community has unique expertise to contribute to this endeavor. This workshop offers a forum for cross-disciplinary discussion, with the aim of seeding collaboration between the research communities.

Tracks of interest include:- Design methodologies for synthetic biology.- Standardization of biological components.- Automated assembly techniques.- Computer-aided modeling and abstraction techniques.- Engineering methods inspired by biology.- Domain specific languages for synthetic biology.- Data exchange standards and models for synthetic biology.The workshop will be held on June 6 - 7, 2011 at the San Diego Convention Center, co-located with the Design Automation Conference, the premier conference in the field of electronic design automation with over 10,000 attendees. Registration information will be posted on the workshop webpage: http://www.biodesignautomation.org
For questions, please email info@biodesignautomation.org

-------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Abstract Submission

Abstracts should be two pages long, following the ACM SIG Proceedings templates at http://www.acm.org/sigs/publications/proceedings-templates. Indicate whether you would like your abstract considered for a poster presentation, an oral presentation, or both. Include the full names, affiliations and contact information of all authors. 

Abstracts will be reviewed by the Program Committee. Those that are selected for oral and poster presentations will distributed to workshop participants and posted on the workshop website. 

Abstracts should be submitted by April 5th at: http://www.easychair.org/conferences/profile.cgi?iwbda2011.-------------------------------------------------------------------------------
IWBDA 2011 Collection in PLoS ONE

IWBDA 2011 will have an associated journal special collection in the interdisciplinary open access journal PLoS ONE. Abstract authors will be specifically invited and encouraged to submit to this collection, although submission is open to any paper describing work on IWBDA tracks of interest. Submitted manuscripts will be reviewed according to PLoS ONE standard editorial policies.

-------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Key DatesCall for participation published: January 24th, 2011Abstract submission deadline: April 5th, 2011Abstract acceptance notification: May 1st, 2011Workshop: June 6th & 7th, 2011

-------------------------------------------------------------------------------Invited Speakers

Adam Arkin, UC Berkeley
Christopher Voigt, UCSF
Erik Winfree, Caltech

-------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Executive Committee 
                   General Chair: Douglas Densmore, Boston UniversityGeneral Secretary: Leonidas Bleris, UT DallasProgram Committee Chairs:  Xiling Shen, Cornell; Smita Krishnaswamy, ColumbiaPublication Chair: Jacob Beal, BBN TechnologiesIndustry Liaison Chair: Jonathan Babb, MITFinance Chair: Natasa Miskov-Zivanov, University of Pittsburgh

-------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Program Committee

J. Christopher Anderson, UC BerkeleyAdam Arkin, UC BerkeleyJacob Beal, BBN TechnologiesJonathan Babb, MITLeonidas Bleris, UT DallasKevin Clancy, InvitrogenDouglas Densmore, Boston UniversityDrew Endy, StanfordAbhishek Garg, Harvard UniversitySoha Hassoun Tufts
Mark Horowitz, StanfordAlfonso Jaramillo, Ecole PolytechniqueYannis Kaznessis, University of MinnesotaEric Klavins, University of Washington
Heinz Koeppl, ETH ZurichTanja Kortemme, UCSFSmita Krishnaswamy, Columbia
Vishwesh Kulkarni, StrandNatasa Miskov-Zivanov, University of PittsburghKartik Mohanram, RiceChris Myers, University of UtahJean Peccoud, Virginia TechAndrew Phillips, Microsoft ResearchMark Riedel, University of MinnesotaHerbert Sauro University of WashingtonXiling Shen, CornellDavid Thorsley, University of WashingtonChristopher Voigt, UCSFRon Weiss, MITErik Winfree, CaltechChris Winstead, Utah State University